Guide to the Frank and Anne Warner Papers, 1899-2000 and undated, bulk 1933-1985 RL.01345
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Prints and Negatives Series, 1933-1969, 2 boxes
  - Prints Subseries, 1933-1969
    - Lot 5: 1941-1942
      - 5B (17) Beech Mountain, N.C.
        - Unidentified child, Frank Proffitt, and Nathan Hicks. (Box 28, Print 5B: 9)
        - Two unidentified boys. (Box 28, Print 5B: 10)
        - Bessie Proffitt, Rosa Hicks, and Mae Hicks. (Box 28, Print 5B: 11)
        - Frank, Oliver, and Bessie Proffitt. (Box 28, Print 5B: 12)
        - Frank Proffitt, Roby Monroe Hicks (back to camera), Frank Warner, Nathan Hicks, Sam Hicks (with white hat, next to Nathan), Ray Hicks (front center, in front of Sam), Vance Presnell (legs crossed), Linzy Hicks (behind Vance), and Lewis Hicks. (Box 28, Print 5B: 13)
        - Frank Proffitt. (Box 28, Print 5B: 14)
        - Anne Warner at a tobacco farm. (Box 28, Print 5B: 15)
        - Linzy Hicks, Lewis Hicks, Frank Proffitt, and Nathan Hicks. (Box 28, Print 5B: 16)
        - The Proffitts' first house in Pick Britches Valley, N.C.: Anne Warner and Frank Proffitt in front. Others unidentified (Box 28, Print 5B: 17)
      - 5C (8) New York.
        - Anne Warner and a Mohawk woman at the Warners' initiation into the Mohawk tribe at the St. Regis Indian Reservation, N.Y. (Box 28, Print 5C: 1)
        - (Yankee) John Galusha and Frank Warner at Galusha's home in Minerva, N.Y. (Box 28, Print 5C: 2)
        - Anne Warner (forth from left, wearing head-dress and stripe jacket) and Louis Solomon (far right) with unidentified others at the Warners' initiation into the Mohawk tribe at the St. Regis Indian Reservation, N.Y. (Box 28, Print 5C: 3)
        - Frank Warner and Carl Carmer at apartment at 144 W. 12th Street New York City, N.Y. (Box 28, Print 5C: 4)
        - Richard O. Hamilton at apartment at 144 W. 12th Street, New York City, N.Y. (Box 28, Print 5C: 5)
        - (Yankee) John Galusha and his dog Flash. (Box 28, Print 5C: 6)
        - Frank Warner and Louis Solomon at the Warners' initiation into the Mohawk tribe at the St. Regis Indian Reservation, N.Y. (Box 28, Print 5C: 7)
        - Louis Solomon's daughter at in Warners' apartment at 144 W. 12th Street, New York City, N.Y. (Box 28, Print 5C: 8)
    - Lot 6: 1943-1949
      - 6A (1) 1924
        - Jonathan (Jeff) Warner. (Box 28, Print 6A: 1)
      - 6B (2) 1944
        - Mae Hicks and Anne Warner in front of the Warners' apartment building at 144 W. 12th Street, New York City, N.Y. (Box 28, Print 6B: 1)
        - Mae Hicks in front of the Warners' apartment building at 144 W. 12th Street, New York City, N.Y. (Box 28, Print 6B: 2)
      - 6C (3) 1946
        - Jonathan (Jeff) Warner, (Yankee) John Galusha, and Flash at the Galushas' home in Minerva, N.Y. (Box 28, Print 6C: 1)
        - (Yankee) John Galusha, Jonathan (Jeff) Warner, and Lizzie Galusha at the Galushas' home in Minerva, N.Y. (Box 28, Print 6C: 2)
        - (Yankee) John Galusha. (Box 28, Print 6C: 3)
      - 6D (2) 1949
        - Gerret, Jonathan (Jeff), and Frank Warner at New York Times Children's Book Fair. (Box 28, Print 6D: 1)
        - Huddie Ledbetter (Ledbelly). (Box 28, Print 6D: 2)
    - Lot 7: 1951
      - 7A (10) Carl Sandburg.
        - Jonathan (Jeff) and Gerret Warner with two of Carl Sandburg's grandchildren at Connemara in N.C. (Box 28, Print 7A: 1)
        - Frank Warner, Carl Sandburg, and Jean Ritchie in the Warners' apartment at 144 W. 12th Street, New York City, N.Y. (Box 28, Print 7A: 2)
        - Gregory d'Allesio, Unidentified, Jean Ritchie, Frank Warner, Carl Sandburg, Anne Warner, and Mari Jinishian at the Warners' apartment at 144 W. 12th Street, New York City, N.Y. (Box 28, Print 7A: 3)
        - Frank Warner, Carl Sandburg, and Jean Ritchie at the Warners' apartment at 144 W. 12th Street, New York City, N.Y. (Box 28, Print 7A: 4)
        - Frank Warner, Carl Sandburg, and Jean Ritchie at the Warners' apartment at 144 W. 12th Street, New York City, N.Y. (Box 28, Print 7A: 5)
        - Frank and Anne Warner with Carl Sandburg in the Warners' apartment at 144 W. 12th Street, New York City, N.Y. (Box 28, Print 7A: 6)
        - Carl Sandburg and Jean Ritchie at the Warners' apartment at 144 W. 12th Street, New York City, N.Y. [with duplicate]. (Box 28, Print 7A: 7)
        - Gregory d'Allesio, Unidentified, Jean Ritchie (behind Frank), Frank Warner, Carl Sandburg, Anne Warner, and Mari Jinishian at the Warners' apartment at 144 W. 12th Street, New York City, N.Y. (Box 28, Print 7A: 8)
        - Carl Sandburg (back, seated on couch), Anne Warner (just in front of Sandburg), Mari Jinishian (seated in chair, back right), and others Unidentified at the Warners' apartment at 144 W. 12th Street, New York City, N.Y. (Box 28, Print 7A: 9)
        - Mari Jinishian (on couch), Anne Warner, and Carl Sandburg at the Warners' apartment at 144 W. 12th Street, New York City, N.Y. (Box 28, Print 7A: 10)
      - 7B (24) Beech Mountain, N.C.
        - Jonathan (Jeff) Warner, Ronald Proffitt, Gerret Warner, and Franklin Proffitt. (Box 28, Print 7B: 1)
        - Rosa, holding Jean; Ray, holding Leonard, and Rena Hicks. (Box 28, Print 7B: 2)
        - Lee Monroe Presnell. (Box 28, Print 7B: 3)
        - Lee Monroe Presnell. (Box 28, Print 7B: 4)
        - Unidentified, two unidentified children (on porch), Jack Hicks, Gerret and Jonathan (Jeff) Warner (backs to camera), Lewis Hicks (sitting against post), Nathan Hicks (in chair), and Linzy Hicks. (Box 28, Print 7B: 5)
        - Unidentified, Buna Hicks, Unidentified. (Box 28, Print 7B: 6)
        - Lee Monroe Presnell, Unidentified, Buna Hicks, Unidentified (boy in chair), Unidentified child, Bessie Proffitt, Mary Hicks, and three unidentified men. (Box 28, Print 7B: 7)
        - A church on Beech Mountain, N.C.: back: Jonathan (Jeff) Warner, Linzy Hicks. Front: Anne and Gerret Warner, Mae Hicks, and Rena Hicks. (Box 28, Print 7B: 8)
        - Lee Monroe Presnell and Jonathan (Jeff) Warner. (Box 28, Print 7B: 9)
        - Roby Monroe Hicks, Lee Monroe Presnell, Unidentified Child, and Buna Hicks. (Box 28, Print 7B: 10)
        - Rosa and Leonard Hicks at their home. (Box 28, Print 7B: 11)
        - Front: Gerret Warner, Ronald Proffitt, Phyllis Proffitt, Franklin Proffitt, and Jonathan (Jeff) Warner. Back: Bessie Proffitt (holding Eddie Proffitt), and unidentified. (Box 28, Print 7B: 12)
        - Home of Buna and Roby Monroe Hicks at Beech Creek, N.C. (Box 28, Print 7B: 13)
        - Buna and Roby Monroe Hicks. (Box 28, Print 7B: 14)
        - Unidentified, Jack Hicks, Lewis Hicks, Jonathan (Jeff) Warner (partially blocked by Ray), Ray Hicks, Linzy Hicks and two unidentified children. (Box 28, Print 7B: 15)
        - Roby Monroe Hicks. (Box 28, Print 7B: 16)
        - Unidentified, Jack Hicks, Lewis Hicks, Linzy Hicks, Unidentified, and Ray Hicks. (Box 28, Print 7B: 17)
        - J.C. Hicks and Gerret Warner. (Box 28, Print 7B: 18)
        - Frank Proffitt's father's house (1941) at Pick Britches Valley, N.C. Frank Proffitt (back, left) Nancy Prather (in front of Frank), Bessie (next to Nancy), and Oliver Proffitt (in front of Bessie). (Box 28, Print 7B: 19)
        - Buna and Roby Monroe Hicks. (Box 28, Print 7B: 20)
        - The Proffitts' House (1951). Anne and Jonathan (Jeff) Warner (left), others unidentified. (Box 28, Print 7B: 21)
        - Home of Buna and Roby Monroe Hicks at Beech Creek, N.C. (Box 28, Print 7B: 22)
        - All Unidentified. (Box 28, Print 7B: 23)
        - Roby Monroe Hicks. (Box 28, Print 7B: 24)
    - Lot 8: 1952, 1959, 1960
      - 8A (5) 1952
        - Unidentified. (Box 28, Print 8A: 1)
        - Jonathan (Jeff) Warner (far left) and Anne Warner (center, wearing dark jacket). Others unidentified. (Box 28, Print 8A: 2)
        - Orient Point, N.Y.: both unidentified. (Box 28, Print 8A: 3)
        - Anne Warner (wearing white shirt) and Jonathan (Jeff) and Gerret Warner (back, visible between Anne and the man standing with her). (Box 28, Print 8A: 4)
        - Anne Warner and (Colonel) Tom P. Smith in Carl Carmer's living room in his apartment at 144 W. 12th Street New York City, N.Y. (upstairs from the Warners' own apartment at the same address). (Box 28, Print 8A: 5)
      - 8B (21) Beech Mountain, N.C. 1959-1960
        - The Proffitt family: Bessie (wearing white dress, left side) and Frank (lower right). Warners: Anne (seated on stairs), Jonathan (Jeff) (top of stairs, left), and Gerret (top of stairs, right). Others unidentified. (Box 28, Print 8B: 1)
        - Frank Proffitt and Frank Warner at the Boone Hotel in Boone, N.C. (Box 28, Print 8B: 2)
        - Frank Proffitt and Frank Warner at the Boone Hotel in Boone, N.C. (Box 28, Print 8B: 3)
        - Ray Hicks (next to two small boys, left), Frank Proffitt (next to man wearing hat), Lewis Hicks (right, front row). Others unidentified. (Box 28, Print 8B: 4)
        - A crowd of Nathan Hicks' descendants and other relatives at the Hicks house, including: Frank Proffitt (far left), Ray Hicks (next to Frank), Linzy Hicks (next to Ray), and Lewis (next to Linzy), Mary Hicks (to right of and behind Lewis). Others unidentified. (Box 28, Print 8B: 5)
        - A crowd of Nathan Hicks' descendants and other relatives at the Hicks house listening to a recording of Nathan Hicks's story of the bear hunt recorded in 1940. (Box 28, Print 8B: 6)
        - A crowd of Nathan Hicks' descendants and other relatives at the Hicks house. (Box 28, Print 8B: 7)
        - Frank and Bessie Proffitt at their home. (Box 28, Print 8B: 8)
        - Rena Hicks, Anne Warner, and Bessie Proffitt. (Box 28, Print 8B: 9)
        - Ray Hicks, Rena Hicks, Frank Proffitt, and Buna Hicks. (Box 28, Print 8B: 10)
        - The Proffitts' house. (Box 28, Print 8B: 11)
        - The Proffitts' house. (Box 28, Print 8B: 12)
        - At the Hicks house: Rena Hicks (left, wearing sweater), Frank Proffitt (sitting on porch with guitar), Frank Warner (sitting in chair with guitar), Lewis Hicks (next to Frank Warner), Jonathan (Jeff) Warner (sitting on porch with guitar), Ray Hicks (back to camera, wearing black hat). Others unidentified. (Box 28, Print 8B: 13)
        - Rena Hicks, Buna Hicks, Anne Warner, Bessie Proffitt, Mae Hicks, Anna Hicks, Mary Hicks, and an unidentified woman (in front). (Box 28, Print 8B: 14)
        - Frank Proffitt with TRO lawyer in front of the Boone Hotel in Boone, N.C. (Box 28, Print 8B: 15)
        - Rena and Buna Hicks. (Box 28, Print 8B: 16)
        - Franklin Proffitt with Gerret and Jonathan (Jeff) Warner. (Box 28, Print 8B: 17)
        - Frank Proffitt and Buna Hicks. (Box 28, Print 8B: 18)
        - Jonathan (Jeff) Warner, Linzy Hicks, and Gerret Warner. (Box 28, Print 8B: 19)
        - TRO lawyer and Frank Proffitt (on the porch) at the Proffitts' house. (Box 28, Print 8B: 20)
        - Jonathan (Jeff), Frank, and Gerret Warner with Frank Proffitt. (Box 28, Print 8B: 21)
      - 8C (5) Beech Mountain, N.C. 1960
        - Frank Proffitt recording in banjo studio. (Box 28, Print 8C: 1)
        - George's Gap. (Box 28, Print 8C: 2)
        - Proffitt Children. (Box 28, Print 8C: 3)
        - Frank Proffitt in front of the second house he built--his tobacco crop in the background. (Box 28, Print 8C: 4)
        - Frank Proffitt recording in banjo studio. (Box 28, Print 8C: 5)
    - Lot 9: 1961; 1963; 1966; 1969
      - 9A (7) Frank Proffitt at Port Washington ( Long Island, N.Y.) on the Whitneys' Little Yankee. This is Proffitt's first trip north to N.Y. and to the sea. 1961
        - Frank Proffitt. (Box 28, Print 9A: 1)
        - Frank Warner, Frank Proffitt, and Douglas Kennedy. (Box 28, Print 9A: 2)
        - Frank Proffitt. (Box 28, Print 9A: 3)
        - Frank Proffitt and Douglas Kennedy. (Box 28, Print 9A: 4)
        - Frank Proffitt. (Box 28, Print 9A: 5)
        - Frank Proffitt working on a banjo in yard at Farmingdale. (Box 28, Print 9A: 6)
        - Frank Proffitt in New York City, N.Y. (Box 28, Print 9A: 7)
      - 9B (9) Proffitts. 1963
        - Proffitts working on new house at Pick Britches Valley, N.C. (Box 28, Print 9B: 1)
        - Buna Hicks (front left) with two unidentified women. (Box 28, Print 9B: 2)
        - Proffitts working on new house at Pick Britches Valley, N.C.: far left, Frank. (Box 28, Print 9B: 3)
        - Frank and Bessie Proffitt in Asheville, N.C. for the Asheville Folk Festival. (Box 28, Print 9B: 4)
        - Picnic at the Hicks house on Beech Mountain, N.C. Frank Proffitt (just left of center, between a bearded man and a small boy). (Box 28, Print 9B: 5)
        - Frank and Bessie Proffitt in Asheville, N.C., for the Asheville Folk Festival. (Box 28, Print 9B: 6)
        - Frank Proffitt, Alan Lomax, Anne Warner, And Bessie Proffitt in Asheville, N.C., for the Asheville Folk Festival. (Box 28, Print 9B: 7)
        - Frank Proffitt (holding ladder) and others working on the Proffitts' new house at Pick Britches Valley, N.C. (Box 28, Print 9B: 8)
        - Phyllis Proffitt. (Box 28, Print 9B: 9)
      - 9C (4). 1964
        - Proffitt family on the porch of their new house: Phyllis, Frank, and three unidentified others. (Box 28, Print 9C: 1)
        - Anne Warner (far right) and three of the Tillett family. (Box 28, Print 9C: 2)
        - At the Hicks house. Front: Ray Hicks, Frank Proffitt, Phyllis Proffitt, and 5 unidentified others. Back: Frank Warner, Mae Hicks, Rosa Hicks, and unidentified. (Box 28, Print 9C: 3)
        - At the Hicks house: Front: Ray Hicks, Frank Proffitt, Phyllis Proffitt, and 5 unidentified others. Back: Mae Hicks, Rosa Hicks, unidentified, and Anne Warner. (Box 28, Print 9C: 4)
      - 9D (8) Beech Mountain, N.C. 1966
        - At Frank Proffitt's grave: two unidentified boys, Bessie Proffitt, Rena Hicks, Phyllis Proffitt (holding Charlie), Anne Warner, Nancy Wadsworth Warner (holding infant), and Gerret Warner. (Box 28, Print 9D: 1)
        - Hickses, Proffitts, and Warners: Ray Hicks (back left), Rosa Hicks (middle, in front of and to right of man wearing cowboy hat), Anna Hicks (next to Rosa, on right), Gerrett Warner and Nancy (holding infant, on left) Wadsworth Warner, Anne Warner (just behind Nancy), Phyllis Proffitt (holding Charlie, just right and in front of Anna Hicks), Rena Hicks (next to Phyllis Proffitt), Linzy Hicks (sitting with guitar), Buna Hicks (sitting with fiddle), Hattie Hicks (next to Buna), others unidentified. (Box 28, Print 9D: 2)
        - Back: Anne and Frank Warner. Front: Linzy and Buna Hicks. (Box 28, Print 9D: 3)
        - Phyllis Proffitt's son Charlie at Proffitts' house. (Box 28, Print 9D: 1)
        - Buna and Hattie Hicks at the Proffitts' house. (Box 28, Print 9D: 5)
        - Bethel Baptist Church. Phyllis Proffitt, Rena Hicks, and Anne Warner (far right), others unidentified. (Box 28, Print 9D: 6)
        - Front: Linzy and Buna Hicks. Back: Nancy Wadsworth Warner and Gerret Warner. (Box 28, Print 9D: 7)
        - Frank Proffit's grave. (Box 28, Print 9D: 8)
      - 9E (2). 1969
        - Steve Wadsworth, in the home of Charles and Margaret Coffin in Northville, N.Y. (Box 28, Print 9E: 1)
        - Anne Warner (behind chair), others unidentified in the home of Charles and Margaret Coffin in Northville, N.Y. (Box 28, Print 9E: 2)
    - Negatives (Box 29)
      CLOSED: Original negatives are closed to use.
    - Miscellaneous Photographs: This box contains photographs that have been reorganized into a separate storage unit from other places in the Warner Collection. A photocopy of each photograph retains the original's position in Anne Warner's own organizational structure of the papers, and notes on the photocopies will direct researchers to Box 30, Miscellaneous Photographs, if viewing the originals is necessary. (Box 30)